YAP JEE FUI (JEF)

014 - 9254 934 Jeffyap0927@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/jef-yap-jee-fui-869a2b85/

Starting from an Accounting & Finance background, I have moved into sales & digital marketing role to grow company revenue by RM15mil in 3 years. Competent Sales Executive who grow company by undertakes complex task, meets tight deadlines and delivers financial result. Possesses practical knowledge in financial accounting and business development by analyzing business model and customizing loan facility for customers to boost monthly loan sales by RM500k. Spearheaded 5 self-learning camps which motivates the teenagers to give back to society.

Core competencies include:

Financial Analysis - Business Development - Project Management - Digital Marketing

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Sales Executive cum Project Coordinator, PCS Vision Sdn Bhd

2016 - present

Assistant to Project & Sales Director to achieve sales target of RM50mil yearly and micro monitoring project to maximize company profitability in the same time meeting project deadlines.

- Establishes new customer base & grow company revenue by RM15mil in 3 years via Tender Exercise, Google Ads & Email Marketing.
- Manages existing customer base by obtaining maintenance contract worth RM300k within 2 years & provide updated product solution to them constantly.
- Making presentations to introduce company products and customized solution to new client & consultant.
- Develop & implement customer centric marketing strategies across website via better content creation.
- To spearheaded communicate between sales & production team to develop new customer solution.
- Maximized profit margin delivery by managing sourcing efficiently & provide credible products offers that met customer needs.
- Coordinator for RM10mil project who simplify complex communication between different stakeholders & vendors, meet tight deadlines & deliver quality aftersales services.
- Successfully co-managed & handover RFID Bus Terminal Project, Parking System Project and Public Address System for KTMB with value over RM22mil.
- Generate project financial analysis & cash flow forecast report for monthly management review.
- Ability to build good clientele relation with MNC company, i.e.: Genting Malaysia Bhd, MRCB Bhd, Prasanara Bhd, CRRC Sdn Bhd.

Credit Analyst, Public Bank, Bandar Puchong Jaya

2015-2016

Prepares credit analysis write up for senior management by accessing credit information and financial statement to examine applicant's condition and monitor the compliances of bank regulations during loan processing stage.

- Cross-sell bank products ie: savings account, insurance and credit cards to maintain branch performance.
- Expands customer base through meeting monthly loan acceptance target of RM2mil.
- Completed Public Bank TalentMAX Graduate Trainee Programme.

QUALIFICATION

Data Science & Python Programmer, University of Michigan

2018

• Retrieve data from SQL, web, CSV or Excel to process and visualize data using Python language.

Digital Marketing, Next Academy

2017

- Created a Landing Page for online music tutor business via wix.com.
- Launched Facebook and Google Campaign to turn page visitor into leads by crafting suitable marketing content.
- Well trained in Facebook Ads Manager & Google Analytics.
- Creative content creation which suits promotional campaign for online music tutor page.
- Executed SEO on Google Ads for own online music tutor business.

Bachelor of Business (Accounting, Banking & Finance) Victoria University, Australia

2012-2014

 Developed 2 profitable business plans in Fruit Juice Business and Vending Machine Sector with team members of 5 under Applied Business Challenge subject.

LEADERSHIP ROLE

President, Sunway CPA Australia Student Charter

2012-2014

Directed the entire membership of 35 in a well-rounded program of activities & projects.

- Initiated a 3 days 2 nights' camp (*B*∞*yond*) to bond 74 VU students from various academic backgrounds.
- Generated club funds of RM3k by developing innovative marketing strategy in organizing CPA Talk, Industrial Visits, Industrial Forums and CSR Projects for Sunway University students.

VOLUNTEERING EXPERIENCE

Camp Leader & Volunteer, World Vision Malaysia

2012-2018

- Volunteer for SJK(c) Kepong Baru to manage activities & coordinate event flowing since 2014.
- Organized 30-Hour Famine Camp for total over 500 secondary school students and volunteers in 2012 & 2013 to spread awareness of poverty & hunger crisis in developing countries.
- Successfully raised donation of RM 18,150 with 200 participants in 2012 & RM 22,450 in 2013 with 280 participants to support the poor's community development.

REFEREES

Ms. Fong Yen Foon
Lecturer in Accounting Coordinator
Club Advisor of SCSC
Australian University Programme
Email: yenfoonf@sunway.edu.my
Phone Number: 019- 359 8031

Ms.Phoebe Than Mentor

Sunway Mentoring Programme Phone Number: 016- 222 3304

Ms. Mandy Soh Branch Manager

Public Bank Bandar Puchong Jaya Email: BPJBM@publicbank.com.my Phone Number: 03- 5882 4110

Andy Yip Project & Sales Director PCS Vision Sdn Bhd

Email: andy@pcsvision.com.my Phone Number: 012-2177 220